Children can be such monsters.
Abigail is a horror, thriller, crime film directed by Matt Bettinelli-Olpin.
A group of criminals kidnap a teenage ballet dancer, the daughter of a notorious gang leader, in order to
obtain a ransom of $50 million, but over time, they discover that she is not just an ordinary girl.
After the kidnappers begin to diminish, one by one, they discover, to their
increasing horror, that they are locked inside with no normal little girl.
Joey, played by Melissa Barrera.
Frank, played by Dan Stevens.
Abigail, played by Alisha Weir.
Rickles, played by William Catlett.
Sammy, played by Kathryn Newton.
Peter, played by Kevin Durand.
Abigail is a 2024 American vampire horror comedy film directed by Matt
Bettinelli-Olpin and Tyler Gillett, and written by Stephen Shields and Guy Busick.
It stars Melissa Barrera, with Alisha Weir as the title character alongside Dan Stevens, Kathryn
Newton, Will Catlett, Kevin Durand, Angus Cloud, and Giancarlo Esposito in supporting roles.
The film follows a motley group of hired criminals who kidnap the ballerina daughter of a
powerful underworld boss, unaware of something sinister about the family.
Originally an adaptation of Dracula's Daughter (1936), the film was announced to be in development in April 2023, with
Bettinelli-Olpin and Gillett attached as directors, and Shields and Busick hired to write the screenplay.
It was also announced that the film would be a co-production between Bettinelli-Olpin, Gillett, and Chad Villella's Radio Silence
Productions, James Vanderbilt, Paul Neinstein, and William Sherak's Project X Entertainment, and Tripp Vinson's Vinson Films.
Abigail had its world premiere at the Overlook Film Festival on April 7, 2024, and was
theatrically released in the United States by Universal Pictures on April 19.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and
grossed $43 million on a $28 million production budget.
The film explores themes of ransom, vampire, kidnapping, halloween, dark comedy.
The tone is dark and intense.